<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>uname Linux</title>
    <link>https://unamelinux.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on uname Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://unamelinux.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Build</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker-build/</guid>
      <description>If you need a refresher here are the first two posts in the series, Linux Containers and Docker and Docker Compose and Volumes.
Before moving on to other Linux container platforms, I&amp;rsquo;d like to focus on one more Docker command, docker build. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to slightly alter existing images, or create entirely new images not available on the Docker Hub. Building images is relatively straight forward once you get a feel for the syntax of Docker images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Compose and Volumes</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker-compose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker-compose/</guid>
      <description>In the first post of the container series Linux Containers and Docker, I introduced Linux Containers and Docker, as well as how to use the Docker CLI and basic management of containers. In this second post of the series I turn my focus to my favorite Docker management tool, Docker Compose.
Docker Compose is a container management tool for Docker, written in Python, and it is a game changer. While managing a single container with Docker is doable, throwing any additional containers in the mix quickly makes management tedious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Containers and Docker</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker/</guid>
      <description>Containers have radically changed how computer systems and applications are built, managed, and deployed. At home I deploy a combination of containers and VMs for my own personal use.
Building Blocks While similar to virtualization, containers have several key differences. Each virtual machine created by a hypervisor has its own kernel and emulated hardware. Containers share the same kernel as the host and isolate application processes from the rest of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XPS 13 Tweaks</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/xps13tweaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/xps13tweaks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had my Dell XPS 13 for about six months now and thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a quick review and summarize some of the tweaks I&amp;rsquo;ve made over time. In August 2019 I purchased a Developer Edition Dell XPS 13 9380 which came with Dell&amp;rsquo;s version of Ubuntu pre-installed. Preferring Canonical&amp;rsquo;s stock version of Ubuntu, the first thing I did was install Ubuntu 19.04 on the new laptop.
The screen of the XPS 13 is fantastic with great color and clarity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Samba</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/samba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/samba/</guid>
      <description>As a first post I thought I would tackle a topic I initially avoided for quite a while, Samba. Setting up a Samba server can be incredibly simple and is a great first step to setting up your own personal cloud at home.
Sharing files via Samba allows me to go from my desktop to my laptop without skipping a beat. I can also feel at ease because my sensitive files are password protected and remain solely on the LAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/privacy/</guid>
      <description>This website does not contain any trackers or cookies.
No personally identifiable information is collected on this site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/license/</guid>
      <description>Copyright 2020 Peter Buffon
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an aspiring sys admin, coder, and Linux enthusiast.
Over the past five years or so I&amp;rsquo;ve become increasingly interested in computers. It all started with a long time dream of building my own computer, which I accomplished in 2014. I grew up with Macs, but I began to have an itch to tinker and I found myself installing Ubuntu on my new desktop rig. This path eventually led to installing Arch, but nowadays I find myself going back and forth between Fedora and Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>If you have any questions, comments, or just want to reach out feel free to contact me via Twitter or Telegram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theme</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/theme/</guid>
      <description>The blog was generated using Hugo and is hosted on GitHub Pages using Cloudflare for DNS. I developed the theme myself using HTML, CSS, and a bit of Golang to piece everything together.
The design of the blog itself was an experiment to create a static website using HTML and CSS. I&amp;rsquo;m going for simplicity and speed here with the potential for further experimentation in the future.
Right now the Hugo theme code for this site is fairly specific (and a little messy), but I do plan on simplifying and generalizing it in the future so I can release it as a theme on themes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>