<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>containers on uname Linux</title>
    <link>https://unamelinux.com/tags/containers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in containers on uname Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://unamelinux.com/tags/containers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WireGuard</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/wireguard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/wireguard/</guid>
      <description>Organizations spanning more than one site often use Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) to protect sensitive data sent from site to site. VPNs allow private networks to be extended across a public network. Most software VPN implementations utilize encryption to further protect data in transit.
Two of the most common VPNs, IPsec and OpenVPN, are long established and feature rich, but often difficult to set up and deploy. A while ago I attempted to set up a IPsec VPN on my home pfSense firewall, but gave up because of the complex authentication setup required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC and LXD</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/lxc-and-lxd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/lxc-and-lxd/</guid>
      <description>Continuing the container series naturally brings us to LXC and LXD. For a background on Linux Containers and an introduction to Docker, see Linux Containers and Docker. The rest of the container series posts can be found here.
 LXC   Engineers from IMB developed LXC in 2008. LXC layered userspace tooling on top of the already existing cgroups and namespace technologies. While LXC improved the user experience of deploying containers, security remained an obstacle with the threat of users being able to break out of containers and attack the host system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Build</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker-build/</guid>
      <description>If you need a refresher here are the first two posts in the series, Linux Containers and Docker and Docker Compose and Volumes.
Before moving on to other Linux container platforms, I&amp;rsquo;d like to focus on one more Docker command, docker build. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to slightly alter existing images, or create entirely new images not available on the Docker Hub. Building images is relatively straight forward once you get a feel for the syntax of Docker images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Compose and Volumes</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker-compose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker-compose/</guid>
      <description>In the first post of the container series Linux Containers and Docker, I introduced Linux Containers and Docker, as well as how to use the Docker CLI and basic management of containers. In this second post of the series I turn my focus to my favorite Docker management tool, Docker Compose.
  Docker Compose is a container management tool for Docker, written in Python, and it is a game changer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Containers and Docker</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker/</guid>
      <description>Containers have radically changed how computer systems and applications are built, managed, and deployed. At home I deploy a combination of containers and VMs for my own personal use.
 Building Blocks While similar to virtualization, containers have several key differences. Each virtual machine created by a hypervisor has its own kernel and emulated hardware. Containers share the same kernel as the host and isolate application processes from the rest of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>