<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>networking on uname Linux</title>
    <link>https://unamelinux.com/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in networking on uname Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://unamelinux.com/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Proxies</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/reverse-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/reverse-proxy/</guid>
      <description>A reverse proxy is a server application that sits in front of one or more web servers and forwards client requests to those web servers. Reverse proxies can be used for (but are not limited to):
 offloading web server TLS encryption reducing server loads by caching static and dynamic content optimizing web content with compression adding basic HTTP access authentication to web servers allowing traffic to multiple web servers though a single IP address  For this post I will set up a reverse proxy on an Ubuntu 20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WireGuard</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/wireguard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/wireguard/</guid>
      <description>Organizations spanning more than one site often use Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) to protect sensitive data sent from site to site. VPNs allow private networks to be extended across a public network. Most software VPN implementations utilize encryption to further protect data in transit.
Two of the most common VPNs, IPsec and OpenVPN, are long established and feature rich, but often difficult to set up and deploy. A while ago I attempted to set up a IPsec VPN on my home pfSense firewall, but gave up because of the complex authentication setup required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Machines</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/virtual-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/virtual-machines/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Samba</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/samba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/samba/</guid>
      <description>As a first post I thought I would tackle a topic I initially avoided for quite a while, Samba. Setting up a Samba server can be incredibly simple and is a great first step to setting up your own personal cloud at home.
Sharing files via Samba allows me to go from my desktop to my laptop without skipping a beat. I can also feel at ease because my sensitive files are password protected and remain solely on the LAN.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
