<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on uname Linux</title>
    <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on uname Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://unamelinux.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Build</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker-build/</guid>
      <description>If you need a refresher here are the first two posts in the series, Linux Containers and Docker and Docker Compose and Volumes.
Before moving on to other Linux container platforms, I&amp;rsquo;d like to focus on one more Docker command, docker build. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to slightly alter existing images, or create entirely new images not available on the Docker Hub. Building images is relatively straight forward once you get a feel for the syntax of Docker images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Compose and Volumes</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker-compose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker-compose/</guid>
      <description>In the first post of the container series Linux Containers and Docker, I introduced Linux Containers and Docker, as well as how to use the Docker CLI and basic management of containers. In this second post of the series I turn my focus to my favorite Docker management tool, Docker Compose.
Docker Compose is a container management tool for Docker, written in Python, and it is a game changer. While managing a single container with Docker is doable, throwing any additional containers in the mix quickly makes management tedious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Containers and Docker</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/docker/</guid>
      <description>Containers have radically changed how computer systems and applications are built, managed, and deployed. At home I deploy a combination of containers and VMs for my own personal use.
Building Blocks While similar to virtualization, containers have several key differences. Each virtual machine created by a hypervisor has its own kernel and emulated hardware. Containers share the same kernel as the host and isolate application processes from the rest of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XPS 13 Tweaks</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/xps13tweaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/xps13tweaks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had my Dell XPS 13 for about six months now and thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a quick review and summarize some of the tweaks I&amp;rsquo;ve made over time. In August 2019 I purchased a Developer Edition Dell XPS 13 9380 which came with Dell&amp;rsquo;s version of Ubuntu pre-installed. Preferring Canonical&amp;rsquo;s stock version of Ubuntu, the first thing I did was install Ubuntu 19.04 on the new laptop.
The screen of the XPS 13 is fantastic with great color and clarity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Samba</title>
      <link>https://unamelinux.com/posts/samba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unamelinux.com/posts/samba/</guid>
      <description>As a first post I thought I would tackle a topic I initially avoided for quite a while, Samba. Setting up a Samba server can be incredibly simple and is a great first step to setting up your own personal cloud at home.
Sharing files via Samba allows me to go from my desktop to my laptop without skipping a beat. I can also feel at ease because my sensitive files are password protected and remain solely on the LAN.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>